ccel.org 2019-05-31

# CCEL Privacy Policy - Christian Classics Ethereal Library

Because we respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it, we have adopted this Privacy Policy. There are several CCEL services that require the collection of information from you. These services include making purchases through the CCEL Store and signing up with a user name and password to enable you to download books and access community and annotation features. Other services may set cookies on your computer. These include installing books on your computer, annotating books, and managing your personal preferences. 

**The CCEL Store**

The CCEL store works in collaboration with [PayPal](http://www.paypal.com/). PayPal is governed by its own privacy policy. Users concerned about submitting information to PayPal should review PayPal's [privacy statement.](http://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=p/gen/ua/policy_privacy-outside)

We receive from paypal.com only your name, postal address, e-mail address, and the item(s) and quantity you have ordered. This information is used only internally, and it is not sold or rented to other parties. You will not be placed on any mailing lists unless you give permission to do so. 

**Our Use of "Cookies"**

Cookies are small bits of data that we send to your computer. They identify you as a CCEL user and contain information regarding your locally installed CCEL location and your CCEL preferences such as your preferred Bible version and note location. 

The cookies are not used for tracking users outside the CCEL Web site, and they are not accessible by third parties. 

**Web Site Traffic Information**

When you visit this or any Web site, information is available to the site on the pages you view, the time of your visit, the browser you are using, the address of the computer you visit from, and the address of the page you are coming from. We use this information internally only, to better understand user needs and preferences and make the CCEL more useful. We do not share this information with third parties unless required by law, and we do not track Web sites you visit before or after you access the CCEL.

**Our Use and Disclosure of Information**

The CCEL will not sell or rent any of your personally identifiable information to third parties. 

The CCEL does not send unsolicited e-mail to users. Only users who have given permission receive CCEL announcements or e-mail messages from the CCEL. Examples of this include voluntarily joining a discussion group or signing up to receive CCEL's newsletter,. 

**Internet-based Advertising**

CCEL frequently uses ad brokers who place ads on our Web site. While CCEL does not collect or disseminate information from our users (other than the exceptions listed elsewhere in this privacy policy), some ad brokers are able to recognize the types of Web pages that our users have visited through their own ‘cookies.’ Some of these ad brokers will select ads to place on our web site based on past web page activity of our users. CCEL, however, does not share, sell, or distribute this information, nor do the ad brokers obtain this information from CCEL.

CCEL displays ads by Google, which uses the [Doubleclick DART](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx) cookie. This allows Google to display relevant ads based on activity on our site as well as other activity on other sites within the Google Ad Network. Users may [opt out](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) of this system at any time.

 **Notification of Changes**

This policy may be revised over time as new features are added to CCEL or as we incorporate suggestions from our users. The CCEL is not responsible for notifying users of changes to this policy.

We will post the amended Privacy Policy promptly on our Web site so that you can always review what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. Please check the CCEL Web site at [www.ccel.org/info/privacy.html](http://www.ccel.org/info/privacy.html) for the current version of our Privacy Policy.
